A Guide to the Mark A. Weber Collection on Lambda Horizon, 1971-1991 (Bulk, 1984-1989)
Special Collections, Virginia Tech
Special Collections, Virginia Tech
Mark A. Weber Collection on Lambda Horizon, 1971-1991 (Bulk, 1984-1989)
Special Collections, Virginia Tech, Blacksburg, Va.
Ms2014-010
This collection has been digitized and is available online.
0.5 cu. ft. 1 box
The Mark A. Weber Collection on Lambda Horizon includes minutes, correspondence, constitution, handouts, notes, and newspaper and magazine articles concerning the Virginia Tech gay and lesbian student organization, Lambda Horizon, from 1971-1991.
Lambda Horizon. (LGBTA of Virginia Tech); Weber, Mark A.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Acquisition Information
The Mark A. Weber Collection on Lambda Horizon was donated to Special Collections in March 2014.
Alternate Form Available
This collection has been digitized and is available online.
Admistrative History
Established in 1985 as Lambda Horizon, the LGBTA has undergone many transformations. The early goals of the organization included providing a place on campus for members of the university community to meet without judgement, to help education the campus community, and to create a positive image of people, regardless of orientation.
During the early 1990's the organization changed its name to LGBT and later to LGBTA. Most recently, they have changed their name to HokiePRIDE of Virginia Tech. In 1998, the organization became a University Chartered Student Organization and began the Safe Zone program. Safe Zone was a collaborative effort between the Dean of Student's office, the LGBTA, the LGBT Caucus, and the Office of Equal Opportunity and Affirmative Action. Today, the organization's main focus is programmatic, not political.
The current mission is to work to promote an environment of equality, understanding, and harmony for people of all sexual orientations, sexualities, gender identities and expressions by providing a LGBT Resource Center and campus-wide programs to raise awareness, community visibility, and increase support.
For more information on the current organization, see their website: http://www.hokiepride.org.vt.edu/
Scope and Content
The Mark A. Weber Collection on Lambda Horizon includes minutes, correspondence, constitution, handouts, notes, and newspaper and magazine articles concerning the Virginia Tech gay and lesbian student organization, Lambda Horizon, from 1971-1991. The collection includes materials regarding the AIDS education committee, which was a primary focus of Lambda Horizon. In addition, the constitution of the Gay Alliance, a previous student organization, is included.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged in four series, based on content and type of materials. Materials within each series are in chronological order with undated items at the end of each folder.
Series I: Administrative Files, 1971-1987, includes documents relating to the founding and continuing activities of Lambda Horizon. In addition the constitution and bylaws for the organizations, there are meeting minutes, funding requests, correspondence, and proposals to the university.
Series II: AIDS Education Committee Papers, 1984-1989, contains materials relating to the AIDS Education Committee, which was sponsored by and included members of Lambda Horizon. There are meeting minutes, hand outs, promotional flyers, and a scrapbook.
Series III: Events/Programs, 1984-1989, consists of papers from sponsored events, invitations to parties held by members, and publicity files.
Series IV: Articles and Clippings, 1985-1991, includes copies of magazine and newspaper articles relating to Lambda Horizon and gay and lesbian issues. In addition, there is a file on the resignation of Sandra Sullivan.
Index Terms
Corporate Names:
Gay Alliance at Virginia Tech.; Lambda Horizon. (LGBTA of Virginia Tech)
Persons:
Weber, Mark A.
Subjects:
University Archives; University History; Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University
Contents List
This collection has been digitized and is available online.
- Series I: Administrative Files, 1971-1987, n.d.
  - Gay Alliance Constitution, c.1971 (Box-folder 1-1)
  - Proposal for Lambda Horizon (Box-folder 1-2)
  - Lambda Horizon Constitution and By-Laws, 1985 (Box-folder 1-3)
  - Dues and Donations, 1985, n.d. (Box-folder 1-4)
  - Lambda Horizon Objectives and Letterhead, 1986, n.d. (Box-folder 1-5)
  - Lambda Horizon Meeting Synapses, 1986, n.d. (Box-folder 1-6)
  - Budget Requests, c.1986 (Box-folder 1-7)
  - Correspondence, 1986-1989, n.d. (Box-folder 1-8)
  - Proposal for a University Designated Staff Position for Gay Student Concerns, 1987 (Box-folder 1-9)
  - Handouts and Questionnaires (Box-folder 1-10)
  - Meeting Notes (2 folders) (Box-folder 1-11 to 1-12)
- Series II: AIDS Education Committee Papers, 1984-1989, n.d.
  - AIDS Education Committee Scrapbook, 1985-1986 (Box-folder 1-13)
  - AIDS Education Committee Meeting Minutes, 1985-1987 (Box-folder 1-14)
  - AIDS Education Committee, 1986 (Box-folder 1-15)
  - AIDS Education Forum Chronology, 1986 (Box-folder 1-16)
  - AIDS Education Committee, University Policies (Box-folder 1-17)
  - AIDS Questionnaire (Box-folder 1-18)
  - "Matthew: If a Tree Should Fall" by Ann Goette (Box-folder 1-19)
- Series III: Events/Programs, 1984-1989, n.d.
  - Gay Awareness Week, 1984-1986 (Box-folder 1-20)
  - Life Fest, 1989 (Box-folder 1-21)
  - Bowling for Bus Shelters (Box-folder 1-22)
  - Event/Party Invitations (Box-folder 1-23)
  - Publicity (Box-folder 1-24)
- Series IV: Articles and Clippings, 1985-1991, n.d.
  - Magazine Articles, 1985-1986, 1991 (Box-folder 1-25)
  - Newspaper Articles, 1985-1989 (Box-folder 1-26)
  - Sandra Sullivan, Vice President for Student Affairs, 1988 (Box-folder 1-27)
  - Historical Virginia Tech (Box-folder 1-28)